Sheharyar Naseer

- sheharyar.me
- hello@sheharyar.me
- +1.631.572.7363
- sheharyarn
- sheharyarn
- in sheharyarnaseer

Skills

Ruby on Rails ****

Elixir & Phoenix ****

Node.is ****

Android ****

DevOps ★★★☆☆

UX / UI ***

I'm a true full stack developer with years of experience developing web and mobile applications and taking them through the complete product development cycle from conception and planning to postdeployment management.

Recent **Projects**

BootDroid

Design & development of an Android app with beautiful UI & animations that allows the user to boot their device in different modes

Kholo.pk

Kholo.pk started out as a personal Development of an online gaming project to bypass digital media censorship in Pakistan while Youtube was blocked for political reasons. At its peak, it served over 500k videos per month on a highly optimized DO instance.

DevFiles

Development of a high-speed file hosting service built on Rails & MongoDB with custom-configured web server for maximum uptime

Crewcade

community which allows users to get sponsorships. It involved recurring online payments, crediting system and implementation of various algorithms

I've worked on lots of different technical stacks and technologies including MongoDB, React, Angular, Sass & Postgres but my best work has always involved Ruby on Rails, Elixir or Android.

Work **Experience**

Freelancer

(2010 - Present)

I've done all sorts of work as a freelancer, from design & development of web and mobile apps to post-development work such as server and DB administration. Most of my projects have been related to Rails, DevOps, MongoDB and Android.

MEAN Developer

Full-Stack Engineer at Caremerge (2015)

Caremerge is a Senior Living and Healthcare focused startup based out of Chicago. I designed and developed one of their main medications module in Node.js, Angular, Stylus and Webpack; driving massive sales to the their product.

Rails & Node.js Developer

Full-Stack Developer at Qwexar (2012 - 2014)

At Qwexar, I was involved in a lot of different projects. Some were simple CRUD Apps, others involved in-depth analytics and complex database schema. One of my main projects here was the Backend Optimization of Smallnest, the iOS app of a silicon valley startup. I also had to set up a web administration backend where the team could see detailed statistics and data reports and predict future trends.

See my LinkedIn for more work history

Education

New York Institute of Technology

Masters in Computer Science (2017 - Present)

National University of Sciences & Technology

Bachelors in EE Telecom (2010 - 2014)

Punjab College of Science

Pre-Engineering (2008 - 2010)

Beaconhouse School System

Matriculation (1992 - 2008)

Other

Open Source

I'm a very passionate advocate of Open Source technologies and a regular contributer myself. I've opensourced multiple Ruby Gems and Elixir Packages along with countless scripts that are being used by developers and agencies across the world

StackOverflow

I contribute a lot of my time answering questions on StackExchange; So much so, that I have a total of **27k reputation** on the network with over 85% from StackOverflow alone. I'm rank among the top 15 users from Pakistan and in the top 0.2% of all of StackOverflow.

Speaker & Writer

I share what I learn, so I regularly blog about a wide range of topics regarding software development. I've given a few talks in the past on different OpenSource technologies & also have been contracted by DigitalOcean to write technical articles for them

Google Developer Group

As the technical lead of GDG Lahore, I focus a lot on developer evangelism with my team; organizing events, workshops and developer conferences in Pakistan as a way to empower the emerging developer community here